Josue Ramirez, Software Developer with Education Experience

(909) 705-6258, josue67ramirez@gmail.com

LINKS

Portfolio, LinkedIn

PROFILE

Motivated Developer with a background in education and experience building web applications and full-stack applications. Skilled in JavaScript, React, Node.js, and integration of APIs to create accessible, user-focused solutions, using maintainable code, and bridging technical solutions with user needs. Bilingual in English and Spanish.

Technical Skills

- Languages: JavaScript (ES6+), HTML5, CSS3
- Frameworks/Libraries: React, Node.js, Express
- Tools: Git, GitHub, VS Code
- Databases: NoSQL
- Other: Web Accessibility (a11y), Responsive Design, Bilingual (English/Spanish)

APPS

Projects

Dream App – Full-Stack AI Web Application

- Integrated OpenAI API to generate images and optimize backend requests.
- Designed responsive, accessible UI components.

Movie App – Full-Stack using Appwrite for database

- Using React for front end and using Appwrite for database storage based on query.
- Ensuring responsive design and use of Tailwind.

Pomodoro Timer – HTML, CSS, JavaScript

- Developed timer and integrated to-do functionality for user task tracking.
- Applied best practices in responsive UI and accessibility.

View more projects at: github.com/josueramirez1 or https://josueramirez1.netlify.app/

EMPLOYMENT HISTORY

Sep 2021 — Present

Special Education Specialist, Options for Youth

Chino/Remote

- Integrated educational technologies to improve student learning outcomes, aligning software solutions with user needs.
- Leveraged data to optimize instruction and workflows.
- Collaborated with colleagues and stakeholders, refining processes through iterative improvements.

Nov 2019 — Sep 2021

Education Specialist, Gorman Learning Center Redlands/San Bernardino

- Supported hybrid instruction with digital tools, ensuring accessibility and usability.
- Communicated technical and non-technical information to staff and students.

Aug 2018 — Nov 2019

Special Education Teacher (SDC), Redlands Unified (Moore Middle School)

Redlands

- Created inclusive lesson plans incorporating assistive technologies.
- Focused on building foundational academic and social skills.

EDUCATION		
Mar 2021 — Jun 2021	Education Specialist Clear Credential, Riverside County	Riverside
Mar 2016 — Jul 2018	Masters in Special Education w/ Education Specialist Preliminary Credential, National University	Riverside